# 我头一次见到XB要加热 闻闻这味
(Da Ye): This is the first time I saw anyone heat their Sprite. (Er Bai): Smell it.
# 意想不到的 多简单
(Da Ye): Very unexpected. (Er Bai): So simple.
# 本来我这冒着汗呢 唰一下就凉半截儿
I was sweating just now, now I’m all cooled down.
# 话梅和XB的结合 真是完美
The combination of Huamei and Sprite is just perfect!
(Huamei: pickled plums)
# 很简单 话梅 冰糖 还得黄冰糖
Very simple, Huamei, Rock sugar, it must be brown rock sugar, -
# 这有点儿XB就行了
and a little bit of Sprite.
# 这西红柿你看洗干净了 烫一下
You see these tomatoes, I’ve already washed them, we will blanch them.
# 烫一下待会咱把皮给它剥了
Let’s blanch them and peel them after.
# 这就差不多了 一分钟
This is about done, about a minute.
# 今天二伯透着精神
Today Er Bai looks very energetic, aye?
# 拿开水烫一下 然后拿凉水一激
We blanch these in boiling water, and immediately submerge them into cold water.
# 大爷您看见没有
You see this, Da Ye,
# 咱们先把皮剥了第一步
Let’s peel the tomatoes first.
# 这个其实是夏天一个很应季的菜
This is a very seasonal dish for the summer.
# 吃完了也很舒服
Very cozy eating it
# 大爷知道 这菜不是一个老的传统菜
Da Ye, you know, this is not a traditional dish.
# 是一创新菜
(Da Ye): It’s a rather innovative dish.
# 你看最早大爷 咱们吃过那什么
You see, Da Ye, back in our days, we used to eat, em,
# 苦瓜 然后刨成极薄的片
bitter gourd cut into very thin slices.
# 然后XB往里一砸 直接冰箱一镇
Dump it in the Sprite and throw it into the fridge.
# 夏季的应季小凉菜 吃着舒服
Seasonal cold dish for the summer, very cozy.
# 有的网友说了 想学正规的菜
Some of our subscribers want to learn traditional and authentic dishes,
# 我们不能不满足
we must satisfy their requests
# 有的网友说我学点接地气的
Some others said they want to learn something more down to earth
# 我家里能做的 我们都得兼顾到
Something that they can cook in home kitchen, we will entertain them both.
# 大爷你看这个菜看似简单
Da Ye, this dish looks simple,
# 影响菜的主要质量就是这个皮
the key factor to the texture is the tomato peels.
# 这一泡这味就能进去了
The flavor goes in once we peel and soak them.
# 要不剥皮这菜质量大打折扣
If we do not peel the tomatoes, the quality and texture will suffer.
# 口感就不对了
The texture won’t be right.
# 大爷您看见没有 这皮就干净了
Da Ye, look, now all the peels are gone.
# 好 冲洗一下
Alright, let’s wash those.
# 下一步你看见没有
Next step, right.
# 我们的菜很简单 话梅
Our dish is simple. Huamei
# 这第一次看见
This is the first time,
# 我头一次见着XB要加热
I saw Sprite being heated.
# 别弄太多 你闻闻这味
Not too much. Smell this.
# XB有一种特殊的清香味道
Sprite has a unique aroma.
# 你要用水就不是这味道
If you use water, it won’t smell the same.
# 开火了（话梅）就搁五个就够了
The heat is turned on. Five (Huamei) is enough
# 可多可少 但是也别太多了
This is flexible, but don’t add too many.
# 有个五六粒这个基本就可以了
About five or six should be enough.
# 冰糖不用太多了 你看这个菜多简单啊
No need for too much rock sugar. This dish is so easy.
# 这时候您再煮它一会 您再尝
Let it boil a bit. Try tasting it again now.
# 话梅搁的好
The addition of Huamei is brilliant!
# 这绝对第一口特别意外
The first sip must be surprisingly good.
# 这小甜水一喝 它关键是什么
Taste this dessert soup. The key is,
# 有让你发生意想不到的效果 口味
it has an unexpected (exotic) effect, and taste
# 冰糖融化以后 现在就可以了
Now it’s ready, all the rock sugar has melted.
# 过下箩 话梅里边有黑渣子
Let’s sieve this, there are some dark residuals from the Huamei
# 看 这来块纱布是非常好的
See, it’s good to have a gauze to filter them out.
# 干净纱布 这个渣子完全都给清理干净了
A clean piece of gauze. All residuals are filtered out.
# 然后这西红柿咱也稍微热一下就行了
Now let’s heat the tomatoes a bit,
# 因为刚才（生水）冲洗了一下
since we just washed them with unboiled water
# 好捞 别太开了
Okey, fish them out. Don’t let it boil.
# 漂亮
Beautiful.
# 话梅直接浸在里边
Just drop the Huamei straight in.
# 继续让它释放它里边的味道
Let it continue to release its flavor.
# 泡会儿晾晾 晾晾下冰箱（冷藏）
Let it soak and cool, then we can put it in the fridge (refrigerate, do not freeze).
# 这夏天 这要喝起来 诱人呐
So tempting to drink this in the summer.
# 本来我这冒着汗呢 唰一下就凉半截
I was sweating just now, now I’m all cooled down.
# 看着流口水了 非常漂亮 诱人的东西
It’s mouthwatering. So beautiful, so tempting.
# 我有一个最柔软的秘密您没发现
I have a tightly kept secret that you haven’t discovered.
# 长这么大不吃西红柿
I don’t eat tomatoes, haven’t eaten any in my life.
# 大爷您得喝口汤吧 喝口汤
(Er Bai):Da Ye, at least you have to have some soup (Da ye): Sure, have some soup.
# 这汤是好东西
This soup is good stuff.
# 大爷您尝尝 谢谢
Da Ye, try this. (Da Ye): Thanks
# 今天大热天给您降降温
Cools you down in all this heat.
# 这话梅这种酸 酸的适口
The sourness of the Huamei is just right.
# 先尝汤 凉爽
Have some soup first. Refreshing.
# 我跟你说XB我都很少喝
Let me be honest, I rarely drink Sprite.
# 但是它这个话梅和XB的结合 真是完美
But putting it together with Huamei is just perfect.
# 夏天来一碗这个 绝对是解暑降温
Have a bowl of this in the summer will definitely relieve the heat.
# 这要在摊上卖大爷 这爆款 绝对的
This is definitely going to be trendy if you sell this at a stall.
# 这网友问说
One of our subscribers asked,
# 我蒸出来的包子皮
“The wrapper of my baozi, ”
# 虽然说也能正常起发
“ although they rise normally, ”
# 但是总是没有外面卖的包子
“they never look like the ones sold outside.”
# 皮口感软嫩白细
“the wrapper is not as soft or white, ”
# 而且底部总有一些透馅
“ and the bottom is always broken”
# 请指教
“Please advise.”
# 我不知道这位网友
I don’t know if this subscriber
# 是用老肥还是酵母
used pre-ferment or yeast.
# 以酵母为准
Assuming that yeast was used,
# 因为老肥现在很多人不常用
as not many people use pre-ferment now.
# 因为酵母发了以后
Once you developed the yeast,
# 和面的时候里边要搁一点糖
add some sugar when making the dough.
# 白糖
White suger.
# 但是说家里要有不吃糖的
But if someone don’t/can’t eat sugar,
# 也可以不放
They can skip it as well.
# 吃包子最好用熟馅
It is best to make baozi with cooked filling.
# 尽量别用生馅
Try not to use raw filling.
# 是吧
Right.
# 因为生馅你蒸的时间
Because you would have to steam it for longer
# 就会长
if using raw filling.
# 就容易底蒸漏了
It is more likely to break the bottom (of the baozi).
# 这个时候大约在两个三个小时
Right now it takes about two to three hours,
# 现在按夏季说
Since now it’s summer.
# 两三个小时这面就发了
Two to three hours for the dough to rise.
# 发了以后
Once it rose,
# 要把这个面搁到案板上
Put the dough on the cutting board.
# 揉一揉
Knead it.
# 揉一揉开始做剂儿
Knead it and start making Jizi (small pieces of dough to be rolled out into wrappers)
# 然后就开始包包子
Then the wrapping can begin.
# 你包好包子往哪搁啊
After you’re done wrapping, where to put it?
# 就直接搁到锅里边
Put it directly into the steamer.
# 放上凉水
Pour in cold water (into the pot).
# 刷上油
Brush some oil (on the steamer basket).
# 把包子直接搁屉上
Put the baozi directly onto the steamer basket.
# 然后都包完了
After the wrapping is done,
# 盖上锅盖
Close the lid.
# 饧发
Let it rise.
# 十来分钟
Around ten minutes.
# 一会看这包子
Then you will see the dumplings.
# 不就长起点来了
All risen.
# OK
OK
# 开始开火
Then turn on the heat.
# 开锅算十分钟
Once the water begins to boil, count ten minutes.
# 你蒸了十五分钟坏了
Steaming for fifteen minutes makes it overdone.
# 底儿漏了
The bottom will break.
# 十分钟关火
Turn off the heat after ten minutes.
# 别掀盖
But don’t open the lid.
# 稍微蹲一会
Let it sit for a while.
# 让它闷一闷
Let it continue to steam.
# 让那气回落一下
Let the steam condensate.
# 这包子出来就好了
Then the baozi is done.
# 如果你要用生馅
If you use raw fillings,
# 如果你蒸的时间再长
If you steam longer,
# 醒发的时间也长
Rise the dough longer,
# 出来以后
after it comes out,
# 这包子底下就漏了
the bottom of the baozi will break.
# 尽量吃包子
Try to use cooked fillings.
# 一定要用熟馅最好
When making baozing, cooked fillings are the best,